[
  {
    "question": "What is part of a database that holds only one type of information?",
    "optionA": "Report",
    "optionB": "field",
    "optionC": "Record",
    "optionD": "file",
    "answer": "field"
  },

  {
    "question": " OS computer abbreviation usually means ?",
    "optionA": "Order of Significance",
    "optionB": "Open Software",
    "optionC": "Operating System",
    "optionD": "Optical Sensor",
    "answer": "Operating System"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following languages is more suited to a structured program?",
    "optionA": "PL/1",
    "optionB": "FORTRAN",
    "optionC": "BASIC",
    "optionD": "PASCAL",
    "answer": "PASCAL"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following computer language is used for artificial intelligence?",
    "optionA": "FORTRAN",
    "optionB": "PROLOG",
    "optionC": "C",
    "optionD": "COBOL",
    "answer": "PROLOG"
  },

  {
    "question": "A program component that allows structuring of a program in an unusual way is known as",
    "optionA": "Correlation",
    "optionB": "Coroutine",
    "optionC": "Diagonalization",
    "optionD": "Queue",
    "answer": "Coroutine"
  },

  {
    "question": "The part of machine level instruction, which tells the central processor what has to be done, is",
    "optionA": "Operation code",
    "optionB": "Locator",
    "optionC": "Address",
    "optionD": "Flip Flop",
    "answer": "Operation code"
  },

  {
    "question": "A system program that combines the separately compiled modules of a program into a form suitable for execution",
    "optionA": "assembler",
    "optionB": "linking loader",
    "optionC": "cross compiler",
    "optionD": "load and go",
    "answer": "linking loader"
  },

  {
    "question": "A device that converts mechanical into electrical energy is?",
    "optionA": "solar cell",
    "optionB": "thermocouple",
    "optionC": "chemical cell",
    "optionD": "generator",
    "answer": "generator"
  },

  {
    "question": "What command is used to count the total number of lines, words, and characters contained in a file?",
    "optionA": "countw",
    "optionB": "wcount",
    "optionC": "wc",
    "optionD": "count p",
    "answer": "wc"
  },

  {
    "question": "In Linux,What command is used with vi editor to delete a single character?",
    "optionA": "x",
    "optionB": "y",
    "optionC": "a",
    "optionD": "z",
    "answer": "x"
  },

  {
    "question": "A station in a network forwards incoming packets by placing them on its shortest output queue. What routing algorithm is being used?",
    "optionA": "hot potato routing",
    "optionB": "flooding",
    "optionC": "static routing",
    "optionD": "delta routing",
    "answer": "hot potato routing"
  },

  {
    "question": "Frames from one LAN can be transmitted to another LAN via the device",
    "optionA": "Router",
    "optionB": "Bridge",
    "optionC": "Repeater",
    "optionD": "Modem",
    "answer": "Bridge"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following condition is used to transmit two packets over a medium at the same time?",
    "optionA": "Contention",
    "optionB": "Collision",
    "optionC": "Synchronous",
    "optionD": "Asynchronous",
    "answer": "Collision"
  },

  {
    "question": "In SQL, which command is used to add new rows to a table?",
    "optionA": "ALTER TABLE",
    "optionB": "ADD ROW",
    "optionC": "INSERT",
    "optionD": "APPEND",
    "answer": "INSERT"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the name given to the database management system which is able to handle full text data, image data, audio and video?",
    "optionA": "Full media",
    "optionB": "Graphics media",
    "optionC": "Multimedia",
    "optionD": "Hypertext",
    "answer": "Multimedia"
  }
]
